Agentic workflows [music] tend to
perform better on AWS than anywhere
else. Compute sandboxes, gateways, agent
permissions versus people. A lot of
those are things that we have built
[music] and are building and thinking
actively about.
>> The top frontier labs gobble up every
available GPUs. At the same time, you
want to promote newer companies that are
going to become the enterprises of
tomorrow. How are you thinking about
balancing?
>> From the very beginning of when we
launched AWS, startups [music] have been
the lifeblood of the core of what we do.
These are the innovators that are at the
edge of technology understanding what's
possible. We're very intentional about
keeping capacity [music] available for
the startups. We recently announced
we're going to be buying 2 million
NVIDIA GPUs over the next couple of
years.
>> Your capex is what 200 or
>> $220 billion uh for 26 and we don't
anticipate slowing down anytime soon
because the demand is just massive.
>> With all the debate around AI extension
risk and the hugging face attack, what
are CEOs asking you about all these
things?
Welcome to the podmat. What a time we're
living in. So I have a lot of topics to
talk to you about.
>> Awesome. Thanks for having me. I'm
excited.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. [snorts] So
let's start actually right from the
beginning, right? So you are the first
GM for EC2.
>> Mhm.
>> And that was 2006, right? And today you
guys are what 160 170 billion in
revenue.
>> Yeah. About 169 170 billion. Yep.
>> Yeah. growing 30
>> 37 37%.
>> That's 37% at 169.
>> Yeah, it's that's crazy.
>> There's a ton of o and it's Yeah, it's
it's it's interesting to think about it
from, you know, we're there in day day
day one when we had like, you know, the
first dollar of revenue, but um
>> yeah, and it's, you know, the
interesting thing is we're still at the
early stages of what the business can be
and what the opportunity is for
customers. um most workloads still, you
know, there's a huge amount of workloads
still that live on prem today and the
amount of compute um that people are
doing every single day is is more than
it was the day before. And so you see
the tailwind from AI, you see the
tailwind from migration into the cloud
and um you know the the business has
grown really fast and it's it's been a
super fun part to be a um thing to be a
part of.
>> Yeah, it is. It is. I mean they'll be
writing uh history books about this and
business books about this for a long
time to come. I want to touch on the on
prem that sort of boggles my mind. I
obviously did my best to keep them there
for a long time.
>> You built a lot of stuff on prem back in
the day of trying to now get all of that
to move into AWS.
>> Yeah. So we can talk about that later.
But uh so if you think about EC2 in the
early days and you got your start with
obviously selling to startups and and
today the AWS cloud service
I mean as you reflect on the evolution
what's what stands out.
>> Yeah.
>> Part one and then part two we'll talk
about how this nature of how you serve
startups has changed.
>> Sure. Well like you said actually it's
funny. So I actually interned for um AWS
in 2005 when we were first kind of was
an internal project. It was my business
school internship and my project was
actually to come up with uh an analysis
of who we thought AWS would be most
interesting to and uh the the answer was
startups like probably not surprisingly
and uh and so you know from the very
beginning of when we launched AWS
startups have been the lifeblood of of
the core of what we do for for a number
of reasons. One is the value proposition
is just so attractive what AWS provides
to startups.
>> Um and and we we spend a lot of time and
effort making sure that we're great
partners to the startups helping them
not just provide infrastructure but also
advice and how to get your company up
and running and how to think about your
architecture so it'll scale eventually
and and a whole bunch of things that we
do for the startups. But we also think
that for us it's just good business cuz
>> the startups today are the enterprises
of tomorrow and and you know it's it's
an imprecise number but
>> today we estimate that you know maybe 30
40% of of AWS revenue comes from
companies that well there's a one-time
you know startups in in AWS's lifetime.
So and it's uh you know and so it's fun
to see for us to see the companies grow
over time and and to get bigger and
become enterprises effectively. Um, and
so that's why we invest so much in
startups and why we pay so much
attention to the the brand new, you
know, two people in a garage type
startups. And um, and and not um, and
and not just because of the business
outcomes, but also because that's who we
learn from. These are the these are the
innovators that are at the edge of
technology, understanding what's
possible, uh, pushing our services to
say what they'd want more of, what could
help them go faster, what could help
them achieve their uh, outcomes. And a
lot of times they're pushing more than
the the banks or the healthcare
companies or the governments. The
startups are the ones that are pushing
that envelope. And it really helps us to
be better and make sure that we're ahead
of that wave where the banks are going
to want some tech some capability 5
years down the road that startups want
today.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And uh compared from then to
now
what have the how have the startups
changed and what they want from you?
Obviously
>> they all want a lot of GPUs and we can
talk about that but besides that
>> well I will say uh there's a couple of
things that have changed. One is um you
know startups started at a much smaller
size than than when when when we first
started right they they might have
gotten $10 million of funding and they
had a app idea that they were kind of
slowly iterating on. Now it's like you
know from day one they're valued at a
billion dollars they have $200 million
of funding.
It's like it's a, you know, it's a a a
team and an idea and all of a sudden
they're worth a billion dollars which um
so it's you know I think the
>> they just go from our offices to your
offices.
>> That's right. That's right. Um uh and
you know like the the size and scale and
ambition of the ideas I think requires
more capital. They're they're bigger to
start with. Um they're obviously more
expensive too, right? To you know to um
uh to go after kind of a training a
model or doing something that that a lot
of the folks are doing today. Um, so
that's number one, which is just the
size that they're that that they start
from is is really big. Um, but I would
say number two is uh some things haven't
changed, right? They they actually are
still thinking about, okay, once I
scale, how do I think about an
architecture? Um, how do I think about
um
security? How do I think about
performance? How do I think about having
all the capabilities that I need? How do
I think about setting up my IM setup so
that when I have more than three
employees, this thing is going to work
and scale, which is a lot of times why
they like AWS as opposed to just, you
know, going to a Neocloud or something
like that. They actually need the all of
those other security and and um and
capabilities that that come around from
um from training. Um and so I think
that's that's you know that's something
that hasn't changed and and is exactly
the same. I think the the scale at which
the ramp up um is definitely different
today. I also think increasingly we're
seeing um teams that want a cloud that
is great to work with agents and not
just with people. Um and I think that's
where we've spent a lot of time how do
you think about you know exactly how do
you think about broad scale? How do you
think about performance? How do you
think about um you know an interface
that is you know a well- definfined API
interface that agents can actually
easily traverse and work across. Um, and
so that's also something that we both I
think we were naturally set up to do
well, but that we've actually doubled
down on to ensure things like, you know,
how can you start a database in 3
seconds and and and and really get to um
some capabilities that agents are
excited about?
>> Um, I should have looked, but I haven't
lately. Have you introduced
any specific new services that are
explicitly targeted at agents or people
building agents? I I'd say what we've
done is we've optimized some existing
services that that so that they can both
work for people and agents and it it
because you know sometimes um and and so
the answer is there we definitely have
some services designed for building
agents. So we have things like agent
core and um and bedrock and pieces like
that. But when we look at just taking an
underlying component like S3, right,
which is where the vast majority of
companies store their data and have
their data links. Um it turns out like a
lot of the use cases for people and
agents are similar, but you want to have
um and one of the things that we have in
preview right now or in in beta. It's
called AWS context that allows you to
build a context layer so that agents can
actually more easily find all of the
data they want across your various data
links. Um and so whether you have your
data stored in um Aurora or you have it
in S3 or you have it in somewhere else
in AWS can kind of build this context
layer where when people aren't
necessarily going to access data in that
way but agents actually are happy to go
across lots of those different things.
And so there are some services that
we're building like that but for the
most part you also care about what does
latency look like, what does throughput
look like, how do you make sure that the
underlying engine is actually fast,
scalable, um that they actually care a
lot about tail latencies which is
interesting. um where people are not
they don't always care about the the
P999 S3 latency like agents do care and
get blocked by that and so
>> um that's the thing that we've cared
about for a long time and um from a
performance perspective it's one of the
things that um that really popped that
that's why um aentic workflows tend to
perform better on AWS than anywhere
else. Yeah, obviously we see um a lot of
companies starting out and the very
common refrain of course is that uh
agents are writing all the code for
them, right?
>> And agents are selecting the databases
and
>> the email servers and everything that
you can name it, right? So has there
been a lot of uh thinking that and
obviously they read the documentation uh
has there been a lot of thinking on the
AWS like your
feels funny to say quote unquote legacy
services that have been around for a
decade on how do you rearchitect them.
>> I think there so yes I think there are
some things that we've thought about
actually the core underlying building
blocks I think are in in really good
shape. I think there's a usability layer
um that we're thinking about of how we
make um easier to use for we'll call it
like the very simplest the the the use
case you call out where somebody's just
coding up an app really quickly and they
ask it to deploy. We we find the vast
majority of our customers will go and
tell their coding agent whether it's
Kira, whether it's Claude, whether it's
uh Codeex, they'll they'll say like, I
want to build on AWS, here's my
credentials, here's my stuff. This is
how I want to deploy it. And then the
agents are great and they go do it.
There are use cases though where you're
just you're already not on a cloud,
you're just trying something. You say
deploy. And frankly, a lot of times
that'll go to some of our partners that
have a an easier to use layer on top.
>> Um which we which we love, by the way,
too. and we love um our partners on on
those fronts too. Um but I do think that
there um there are some things that
we're doing where if you're brand new,
you don't already have an AWS, you
already haven't set up your IM. Um today
or we'll say a couple of months ago, it
was much harder to start up an account,
right? You had to it's been like this
for 20 years, but you have to define
your VPCs, you have to define your IM
roles, all these kind of things, which
are actually super important things once
you get to be large. Um, and what we
hear from customers is like it was a
hard trade-off because they know that
they're going to want those n months or
years down the line, but for now they
just kind of want to use the services,
not worry about that.
>> Um, and so what we've actually launched
is if you go create a new AWS account
today,
>> and we're slowly rolling this out. I
don't know if it's actually full all the
way out yet now,
>> but um, you don't have to do those
things. You don't have to give it a
credit card. You can sign up with your
Gmail account. um you get to just all of
those things are handled in default
behind the scenes and within less than
30 seconds you're up and running and can
be and can be operating in AW full AWS
account which is you know for those type
of systems much more what the agents
want to be able to do because they don't
want to have to go through all that
setting up your VPCs and your
>> um uh and and pieces like that. So there
are some things where we're adding kind
of some ease of use to that which we're
we're quite excited about and I've seen
some really positive feedback from
customers on and and we'll keep doing
more things like that over time.
>> And I and just one more thing that which
is the the the great part about that
though is it's not like a a simplistic
account and then you have to migrate. If
you basically say okay now I actually do
want to scale into the or I want to
develop an organization. I want to go
and and kind of fine-tune some of the
things. you can easily come just you're
you're already in a real AWS account and
you can actually then go and do all of
those things later when you need them
and so there's no migration or move
later and so that's part of the hard
work that we really think about which is
how do we make it not a choice for the
customer but an easy on-ramp into the
depth of features that we know customers
um and startups are going to want when
they start scaling.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Got it. And um
what has been some of the hardest things
to accommodate as agents have taken
over? I mean you made a name.
>> This is the way you guys became the
phenomenon that you became was serving
developers, right?
>> Um and then uh infra teams u now
developers are substituted by agents and
pretty soon infra teams are being
substituted by agents.
>> Yeah. Are there what has been some of
the hardest things for you
as the largest service provider in the
world
>> to handle that transition?
>> Well, I you know look I think um like I
said much of our infrastructure was is
>> yeah pretty well set up to handle the
scale um which is good. I I think
there's been a couple of things which
are interesting which are I think
interesting paradigm shifts where um you
could argue that some of our systems are
um I wouldn't say overengineered but um
as an example many agents want to create
a database uh do a little bit of work
and then have the database go away. You
really need that database to have 59s of
durability. Exactly. Right. And so
there's some things that we rethink
there where when you're creating an
Aurora database like as your production
database like you do want five ends of
data, you know, you want you you need
durability, you want availability, you
want all of those things. And for the
agent use case, that's that's arguably
or maybe not arguably like
overengineered for for what we need. And
so, you [clears throat] know, it's hard.
We don't um and we kind of have this
this uh
um a belief that we don't we don't
really want to have like a non-durable
option that's that's going to cause
problems either cuz you never really
quite know if the database that's
created is wants to stay around for a
long time or a short amount of time. And
so we're we're um trying to do the hard
work to think about how do you
accomplish both of those things where
you can create it quickly and throw it
away and you don't really waste a lot of
resources. But um but um but if you do
want it and it can be durable and stay
for a long time, it actually grow into a
big production database. So those are
some trade-offs that we think about
actively as we think about how does the
the the more traditional kind of this is
going to be my production system kind of
capabilities um match with uh with with
some of the more transient nature of the
infrastructure that agents uh want to
use. Um, so that that's one I think, but
there's there's there's a bunch. I think
the um scale and speed and latency of
creation of of durable resources is
another one that's interesting. Um, you
know, I think the other one that we
actively think about too is just are
there new building blocks that agents
are going to want that we just didn't
really need before. Exactly. And so
compute sandboxes,
um, uh, gateways, um, agent permissions
versus people or or or service role
permissions, um, a lot of those are
things that we have built and are
building and thinking actively about cuz
they are just brand new building blocks.
It's not using the existing building
blocks differently, but it's brand new
ones where pretty pretty clearly you
want a different permissions for agents.
You don't just want to give it Ragu's
permissions and let it go do whatever
you can do. you actually want um you
know very time box short-term
permissions to just go do a task. You
actually may not want to give
permissions to a whole tool at all. You
may want to get very fine grain
commissions what an agent's able to do
>> from a sandbox, right? You actually want
a sandbox that um uh you want to
>> virtualization is having its act too.
>> That's right. Exactly. That's and and
they're they're different. It's similar.
It's the same idea, but it's, you know,
how do you have that lightweight and and
think about um unfortunately we've done
a lot of work with um firecracker or our
kind of microVMs.
>> In fact, a lot of the sandbox company
startups use fire.
>> They all use fire which which we
invented 10 years ago maybe or something
like that. And it's it's it's really
purpose-built for I mean it's not wasn't
purpose-built for agents, but it's
actually quite good for agents because
you can spin them up really rapidly.
they have a great security boundary um
and you don't have a lot of that
virtualization overhead that you have
from a traditional large VM. Um, so you
know, I think those are some some new
building blocks that we're thinking
about and um and more emerge every
single day, you know. Yeah. And
>> yeah,
>> so I've rattled enough into agents. I'll
come back to it later, but it's a
fascinating topic.
>> Super cool.
>> But uh let me switch gears a little bit
and ask about something that uh every
one of our startups face and we get
asked most frequently
>> which is how can we get GPUs, right?
>> Yeah. I mean obviously you guys have
running massive GPU farms and increasing
it every day [gasps]
but uh the top frontier labs gobble up
every available GPUs more power to them.
>> How do you deal with the internal at the
same time you want to promote newer
companies that are going to become the
enterprises of tomorrow like you said
>> um how are you thinking about balancing
>> yeah it's capacity needs and these small
companies that don't have a lot of
credit and whatnot. So, well, yeah, it's
a great question. Um, and and a couple
of these things make it more challenging
to one is um the the capex expense
needed to go deploy kind of all of the
compute that everyone needs right now um
is massive, right? And so we are uh I
think
>> your capex the same as what 200 or
something
>> $220 billion uh for 26. It's uh I I by
by at one point I saw that it's you know
it's it's a pretty I mean that is a
larger expense than we've ever had maybe
any company has ever had in a in a
single year. Um and um and we don't
anticipate slowing down anytime soon
because the demand is just massive. And
so at some point you're limited by how
fast can you build data centers, how
fast can you deploy capital, how how
fast can you get memory and chips and
all of those kind of things. Um and so
all of those are at different points
constraints that we're you know whether
it's power data centers capital memory
chips they're all kind of constraints at
various times construction people to
build buildings like you know
construction people are are at a premium
today.
>> Um and so all of those we you know we we
work really hard to make sure happen. Um
and then with the capacity that we are
able to deploy, which is still a huge
amount and and and not enough, we know,
um we really think intentionally about
what is that allocation strategy. And
so, [snorts]
um we're great partners with the the
large frontier labs, the Anthropics and
OpenAIs and and Meta and and other large
customers. And so those folks are are
really good customers of ours.
>> Yep.
>> And uh and we want to make sure that we
invest in them. we have large enterprise
customers whether it's uh sales forces
or or JPMC's or you know other large
companies that that have demand for
fewer numbers of GPUs but or or
accelerators sometimes they want tranium
sometimes they want um uh Nvidia GPUs um
but we want to make sure that we can
support them as well and we're very
intentional about how we make sure that
we have capacity for startups and and so
what we do is we actually do allocate
and we basically say okay we're going to
keep we could you're right we could sell
every single um uh you know GPU or or AI
accelerator we had to probably just the
lab the big frontier labs and call it a
day.
>> Um we choose not to do that because we
actually want to keep growing the the
full ecosystem. They get a large number
but but um we want to keep supporting
>> um a broader set of customers cuz we
actually think that both the whole
ecosystem be more healthy for us.
There's some diversification but it's
also just we know these are going to be
big companies over time. Um and so we
try to support them. Um I saw recently
that we say you know yes in some way
shape or form to something like 60% of
the the requests we eventually get.
Sometimes it's a little bit later
sometimes it's in a different region.
Sometimes it's a slightly different
configuration than the customers are
looking for. Um but we really try to
lean in and and and try to allocate as
much as we can and every single startup
that you have wants more [laughter]
and so you know so we're working hard um
to try to make sure that we have all of
those. Um, but you know, it's it's hard.
Like that's that's it's you know, like
this is the as a lot of people say, it's
a good problem to have. Uh, but it's
it's a problem nonetheless. And um and
we're you know, we continue to look at
at um you know, we we recently announced
we're going to be buying um you know, 2
million Nvidia GPUs over the next uh
couple of years. like we're we're
landing a massive amount of capacity
>> and 2 million
>> 2 million um so you know it's a lot um
and it's over the next couple years but
um and uh and who knows if that's enough
[laughter]
but that's at some point again we're
limited by other other components as
well um but it is we're we're very
intentional about keeping capacity
available for for the startups and I
know it's it's painful to not have
enough but we we keep pushing
[sighs and gasps]
>> and
when did uh your capex
cross
I mean pure AWS. I mean Amazon was a
bigger company.
>> Yeah.
>> Cross like let's call it even 1 billion
or 10 billion a year.
>> Oh, I don't know. I'd have to go back
and look. I'm not sure about that. But
it it's definitely scaled up over the
last couple of years. Um uh in a pretty
meaningful way.
>> The the yeah the AI buildout has has
definitely ramped our our capex
spending. And so I'd say over the last,
you know, call it 3 or 4 years, our our
capex has definitely accelerated um
pretty pretty meaningfully. Um I don't
know when we crossed a billion, but um
given we're 220 now is probably I mean
we we've been spending capex for a while
and the and the company has been really
good about funding that um and obviously
the AWS business is is a good one that
we like to invest in.
>> Yeah. Yeah, of course. And um uh and you
know I think we were for the longest
time actually um we you know we we were
investing ahead of where the demand was
and
>> um you know I think one of the one of
the most painful things is that with the
real ramp of of GPUs like a lot of the
elasticity has unfortunately you know
kind of gone away. Um and so hopefully
we'll get back to in our core compute
and and storage and things that
elasticity is still there and that but
um but you know that um but but so we've
been spending for for quite a bit of
time and and we feel really good about
the spend that we're making now. um
which is you know I think I get lots of
questions sometimes about how you feel
about that spend and like are you
nervous about bubble and other things
like that and I will say you know
>> we um because of the position we have
like one we do take this diversified
approach and so not all of our capacity
is bundled up in one customer and I
think you go to a some of these whether
they're neoclouds or some of the the
other providers out there and
>> you know you'll see sometimes
concentrations of 30 40 50 60% with one
or two customers
>> we're nowhere near that obviously we're
you know singledigit percentages at the
highest and and and usually it's less
than that for one I think we have a lot
less risk on on one particular customer
but also because we have that rich set
of services like AWS is where people
really are coming to launch their
production workloads and so the majority
of our usage today actually is either
core compute and storage and inference
which is part of that application and so
those are the workloads that I think
just aren't going to go away just cuz we
see enterprises getting positive ROI you
go talk to the customers and you say at
the capability today and the cost today
are you seeing positive returns to your
business and almost to a person they'll
say like oh yeah
>> and so you're like well that's not going
to go away there's no bubble in which
they they stop spending on that you know
and so
>> you know and you know this like the VC
model like is every billion dollar
startup going to make it no they won't
but you know that's that's kind of the
game and it's been that's been true for
50 years [laughter] they haven't always
been billion dollar
>> start numbers have changed but the
principles are the principles are the
same right you bet on 10 and one makes
it and pays for the other 10 or whatever
the whatever the percentage is.
Hopefully it's higher than one. Yeah.
Right. And so that that there you know
you saw that with the internet where
there was a bubble and a bunch of of
internet companies didn't make it and
the internet's still a thing
>> and and a lot of the companies that had
durable businesses
>> the Google, Amazon's that others like
that they did pretty well
>> and so for us we think we'll feel really
good about that investment and um and
and and the continued investment going.
>> You guys have a view of the demand
>> that's unparalleled, right? because
you're seeing across the globe, you're
seeing across every segment enterprise
and the big labs and the AI native
companies and so on and so forth. So,
>> if anybody should call it, you should be
able to call it first.
>> I would hope so.
>> Yeah, that's our that's our plan and and
honestly, we spend a lot of time
thinking about it. We're very
intentional
>> um about how we spend um you know, our
shareholder capital and and we think
that we're making great investments. We
have a lot of good protections of how we
intentionally invest that money. But um
but yeah, we're we're very bullish on
and you know, I think Andy's been public
about saying this, we the potential for
AWS is is really really large and over
the next decade, the potential is there
and anytime you have an opportunity
that's that big like you kind of want to
make you want to you want to invest to
go after it
>> and
as the scale of these numbers
go larger and larger, right?
>> Yeah. Has your planning and process
dramatically changed in terms of I mean
you're not writing
>> Yeah.
>> billion dollar checks, you're writing
like $50 billion checks or $20 million
checks or whatever it is.
>> Yeah. Um Yeah. Yes and no. I mean I
think look a lot of times we're the the
we're still very bullish about the
investments and and lean forward but
there there the process. So there's a
lot of things that have completely
changed.
>> Like how do you even estimate 2028
demand? And there's things that we have
to think about now that we just never
had to think about. Um and so
>> if you go back 15 years,
>> um if we needed more power, we asked the
power company to give us another,
>> you know, couple of megawatts or
whatever it was, right? Tens of
megawatts like and they would just give
it to us cuz 10 megawatts wasn't that
much. And uh and that was plenty for us
to keep growing. Um now we have to bring
our own we bring our own power. And so
we we pay for power projects. We pay for
renewable projects. We're one of the
biggest uh renewable power purchasers uh
each year for the last 10 years. Um and
so it's you know we're regularly
bringing on new solar projects, new
nuclear projects, new
>> So you're talking about behind the meter
or are you talking about working with
the operator?
>> We'll do both. Um and so both of those
things and so often times with these
power projects that we bring on um we'll
pay the the capital and and pay for the
project and then it'll go into the grid
and then we'll get credit for that. So
we'll bring those on. Um sometimes we'll
do behind the meter too. like it's it's
a mix at the at the scale that we're
doing. You have to think about all of
those things. Um but um but you know
that's that's planning where you're
thinking you know 20 years out of how
you're going to think about um power,
how you're going to think about
transmission, how you're think going to
think about that um capital and and
that's stuff we'd never had to think
about before. That's planning we just
never had to do. Um but you know we
always had to it's you know the the
other things is when we used to think
about server demand that we needed we
you know we'd have you know multiple
quarter demand things and we'd talk with
our our suppliers and things. Now we we
work multiple years out um just because
the the size is so much that we have to
think about kind of what do we need for
26 we need for 27 what do we need for
28. Um, and so that's but you know, but
it's also one of the value that we bring
to customers, right? That's a thing that
legitimately customers can't do
themselves. Like they're not going to do
power. They're not going to plan their
memory footprint in 2028. Like they're
just that they can't do that. And so
that's one of the real values that we
bring to to our
>> broad set of customers is just that's
just a whole set of things that you
don't have to worry about and that that
we spend a huge amount of time thinking
about.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You guys are
generally, I think for the record, the
largest buyers of practically every
component of a server. Correct.
>> I I don't know that. I don't [laughter]
>> I am sure that we're one of the the the
bigger um uh purchasers of of components
out there for sure. Um and uh who knows
about everyone but uh and it kind of
depends on how you think about them and
how you measure but um
>> so where I was leading to where do you
see the
the constraints being most severe let's
call it 2728 and where do you see the
constraints easing up? Yeah, it's funny.
It's um so uh I'll answer this in a
roundabout way, but um you know uh I
remember that um in undergrad we
actually this was this long time ago and
I never thought this would be like a
useful book that I read but we read we
read the goal and have read the goal
right and so it turns out there's never
one constraint there's always just the
latest constraint and so you have to
think about all of them and as soon as
you hit one there's another one right
and so you know what do you like what is
the constraint that's going to happen in
20 and 28 like I actually don't I think
there will be one. I think it's like
every month for us it's do you have
enough power and then as soon as power
is no longer the constraint you know it
might be memory it might be TSMC
capacity it might be you know HBM it
might be um uh networking components it
could be you know there's a a blip
somewhere in the supply chain and like
you know connectors or whatever it is
right at some point you have to think
about all of those pieces um and it's um
you know it's it's not also the um uh
kind of where they happen matters too,
you know. So it's it may be like, hey,
we have a ton of power in Indonesia, but
we don't have enough in Germany, right?
And so you think about kind of where in
the world you want that capacity, too,
cuz it's turns out that not everything
is totally funible. Some is and some's
not. Um but might be disc drives, it
might be SSDs, it might like we we think
about every single component and we have
you know tens hundreds of thousands of
components all that we track and think
about and um and some we rely on our you
know our um suppliers to to manage some
we direct much of it we directly manage
and uh um and yeah that we have a whole
team that does that and they're
fantastic they're I think they're
industryleading and and we um we kind of
we we saw this problem coming um
probably a decade ago
and really started not just thinking
about okay how many servers do we need
to track but just thinking all the way
through the supply chain you know four
tiers five tiers down what is the
component that that could cause an issue
for us and making sure that we had kind
of guaranteed supply on that
>> um if you think if you remember
>> I don't remember when this was over a
decade ago when there was like the
floods in Thailand and and no one had
disc drives anymore um uh and so that
was
>> there was disc drive crisises and then
there was memory crisis
>> exactly and so you know it's like I
think we think through all of those
things and so we also think about
where's their diversification in
manufacturing like all of those kind of
pieces we try to work through and um and
we're we're never going to be perfect on
it but there's always a different supply
constraint.
>> Yeah. So um
obviously there's a lot of wide ranging
debate about data centers.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. And uh
it's clear that folks like us where we
stand. But do you think as an industry
we have not done a good job
>> of explaining
why data centers are good for America
and
>> generally the world? But uh
>> and how [snorts] do you what's the
internal talk
>> amongst Andy's team
>> on how do we deal with this?
>> Yeah. Well look I I think um and I think
you'll hear more from us over this and I
agree. I think we need to be more vocal
and be more upfront. Um cuz we actually
do a ton that's that's really beneficial
both for the communities we operate in
um for the you know we we think a ton
about how do we bring renewable energy
to these data centers. How do we think
about being water positive?
>> Um actually our our our data centers use
a really really small amount of water.
We mostly use free air cooling. How do
we think about being great participants
in the communities where we are and um
and how do we bring highpaying jobs to
the communities we operate in? Um and
not all data center operators do that.
And I think there are some well there
are some well chronicled examples of
others out there that are not great um
at that and they just
>> don't really pay attention to
regulations. They think that the rules
don't apply or they just you know launch
really quickly without thinking about
those. And I think that it causes
problem for the whole industry because
everybody kind of gets lumped into that.
And so
>> um so look I think we'll be we we I
think you're right. We um you know
vocally is self-critical. We need to be
more vocal about the benefits that we do
bring and think about additional ways
that we can help communities understand
the benefits that that we bring to them
both for the the services they use,
right? If if you usually go to a
community and say, "Well, do you not
want to use Netflix?" And they'll be
like, "No, no, like I I still want
[laughter] Netflix." Like that's it. Um
and um you know like it's important for
us to think about and highlight the
benefits that we bring where I I
recently saw a report where one of the
communities that we operate in
>> the everybody in that county pays $5,000
a year less in taxes because of the
taxes that we bring to that. And we
don't we don't tell them. They don't
even know it, right? It's just invisible
to them. And so I think we just need to
be more um um clear about those benefits
that we bring cuz I think if you told
the communities, by the way, your tax
bill is $5,000 less than it would
otherwise be if we weren't here,
>> they might have a little bit of
different thought about the building
that's over there. Um so and and but but
not everyone does that. Not everyone
kind of um
>> presumably there's more transparency
that's needed.
>> And look, I think much of the data
center um community, not just us, is
actually pretty good actors. And there's
just a few that aren't that um that
>> that kind of I think have have caused
some of the angst recently. And I think
we just need to do a better job of
highlighting, you know, who's who's
being good citizens and who's not.
>> Yeah. And uh before we leave the
hardware topic, uh um I want to touch
upon training.
>> Mhm.
>> And your whole history with building
your own uh chips, right?
>> Um we were one of your first partners
using Nitro a long time ago. Mhm.
>> Uh and since then uh Graviton and you
made tremendous progress. So what was
the thinking that led to saying look
we're going to do our own thing and then
how has that progress been and where are
you
>> it's actually a fascinating story and I
think it's a great example of where um
Amazon AWS will innovate and we'll
iterate over time and continue to think
bigger about what we can do but but um
but kind of prove our way there as
opposed to you know and so takes as an
example um this probably now I 10 it's
probably about 13 14 years ago
we were seeing that there was a pretty
significant um virtualization tax on the
overall number of resources and um and
we were kind of thinking about how do we
our customers were telling us I want
bare metal performance and they you know
they're comparing to having all the
resources of a of a server
>> and so the first thing that we did is
that um we took a a network offload card
and virtualized all of our network
virtualization and pulled it off onto an
offload card so that network
virtualization got closer to to bare
metal performance and back then it was
not quite bare metal but it was close it
was closer
>> and then we got really excited about
that and we said okay what if we could
move storage virtualization off as well
right and and um and none of the network
offload cards could do that and then we
we found this one company who had some
ARM cores on an offload card and they
were doing it for other reasons I can't
remember their original purpose but
we're like could you use those to do
storage virtualization and some of these
other functions and they're like maybe
and so we really iterated with them this
was the product Yeah, this is the team
>> and um and just loved that team like
really innovative, really missiondriven,
really wanting to solve problems.
>> Um and so we acquired them and we said,
look, could you build us a slightly
bigger card that actually could take all
the network virtualization off and
basically give us a bare metal server
that has no virtualization on it, no VM
virtualization, everything is through
APIs on the card. And because we had
this view that one performance would be
much better, resource resource
utilization would be better. Ruby be we
security isolation
>> and security isolation would be much
much better and we tell people you know
could then legitimately tell people we
have no access to any of your VMs that
are running there
>> and and um and this has been a huge
benefit for us for the last decade where
frankly like we've been leading and and
others have been kind of slow to do this
because they this is not a generalized
thing that people can do
>> but um so we got to that and we
basically said look we're we're making a
lot of progress here um what if we take
you know And there's a bunch of ARM
cores that were on this offload card.
And we said, "What if we turn that into
a server?"
>> Uh, and we did that first with Graviton.
It was a very underpowered um very small
server that we launched.
>> Um, and and customers were excited.
They're like, "I'd love to have an ARM
server. This is super interesting." And
so we went down the path and um and
Graviton um you know and part of what we
did is we looked and saw that there's
the the slope of you know ARM cores were
getting faster and where the you saw the
power utilization and and the graph
where they and you knew the intercept
was going to happen for where this
architecture was going to be really good
for for parts and they just needed
somebody to drive the ecosystem and and
get some of the pieces in place. So we
did that with Graviton. Um and
Graviton's been a a runaway hit at this
point. Um,
>> have you been public about what percent
of your fleet is?
>> We land more graviton ships uh uh every
year than um uh than than any other um
type. So it's it's it's very popular. Um
and it's um you know look we they're 20%
cheaper at a 20% better performance and
have been like that for the last kind of
five six years. So that's a it's an easy
value proposition that um and I think
the vast majority something like 90
plus% of our top 100 customers all use
Graviton in some way shape or form
across their fleets. Um and so that's
been a huge win for us and for customers
it's been it's the single big single
easiest way that customers lower their
bill is to move to Graviton.
>> Um they can often we've we've have
examples where people have moved their
whole fleets and cut the number of
servers they had in half.
>> The performance is so much better.
>> It's amazing. And so half a number of
servers, each server costs less. Like
it's it's a it's a big win. And so then
about five, six years ago, we said, you
know, we saw the rise of of AI um
compute happening. Um not nearly
expecting what it was today, but still
saw it was going to be a big material
mover. And so we went in, built our
first chip in and Tranium, and uh we're
now um you know, in market with the
third generation in Tranium 3. And um
have seen fantastic results. So, it's,
you know, we're we're sold out um uh for
capacity through probably maybe towards
the end of next year or something like
that. And and and we we're trying to
again we're trying to figure out how we
can save some capacity and get startups
to be able to use some of the capacity
cuz it's uh we see great results. So,
most of you know the the the majority of
of traffic on Bedrock all runs on
Tranium. Um and we have um great deals
with both Anthropic and OpenAI to build
on top of Tranium. um as well as a a a
set of um of smaller startups and you
know I think we have half dozen to a
dozen startups that are building on top
of tranium now too
>> and uh
>> so now the name suggests it's a training
chip
>> yeah we're back
>> but everybody's using it for inference
too
>> so where is the lean architecturally and
where is it going
>> it's a good point um look the vocally
self-critical we're terrible at naming
and so it's not it's not our strength
originally we had a chip called
inferentia for inference and training
for training for training And then as
the models got bigger and bigger and it
turns out you actually want to run the
inference on these really large systems,
it turns out it turns out that tranium
is actually maybe the best inference
chip on the market right now.
>> Um from a a per absolute performance and
cost performance point of view.
>> Um and so um
>> is it better memory memory bandwidth?
Where is the
>> it's just it has it has um it's just
architecture is a little bit different
than than um uh than others and it's
much cheaper. Um, and so from a cost
performance perspective and absolute
performance perspective, tranium is
great. Um,
uh, and so we're, you know, we we use it
a ton for, um, for inference and, and,
and that's going to say, Bedrock, um, it
drives much of the Bedrock um, uh,
inference today. And, um, but it's also
a good training chip, too. And it's, you
know, I think we're we we, you know, a
lot of our broad set of customers usage
is not in training models, but is in
using it. And so that's where a lot of
people get to use it under the covers,
and that's where we're excited about it.
But um but a lot of the big customers
are interested in it for training
clusters as well. And particularly as
you get to tranium 3 and four um uh
which we've announced we haven't we
haven't launched trainium 4 yet but
announced it. Um folks have kind of
looked at that architecture and said
like yeah that's the future of where I
want my training clusters to be as well.
So we're we're quite excited about the
future where that goes for these really
broadscale training clusters also.
>> But um but yeah it's built.
>> Yeah. Now uh let's get back to uh
talking about agents but from a
perspective of uh large enterprises or
large medium enterprises.
>> Yeah.
>> Where are they in their adoption? Um
>> and uh have they what sort of benefits
are you seeing them
>> reap already and what is the roadmap for
them as far as you can tell from your
vantage point?
>> Yeah, it's it's a really good question.
And I think it's one that um that we've
spent a lot of time thinking about. And
when I talk to customers all out there
um today, they view, you know, they're
getting a lot of value out of what
they've done today. And I would say the
agents that most enterprises have built
are are relatively simple and
straightforward. Um and they're starting
to think about um and they're um mostly
>> non-aututonomous, right? They're still
kind of people in the loop, if you will.
And so I think we're and and by the way,
there's customers are still getting lots
of value out of that today. And so
they're really thinking about how do I
have these be autonomous but in a safe
way. And I think there's two things that
that I think hold customers back today
from just continuing to to scale. And
it's it's already a pretty big business
today, but I think it's it has a massive
opportunity to really change
every single customer out there and
every single workflow and and really
thinking about it. And so number one is
just how to think about it. I think what
we originally saw was that enterprises
had a workflow and they're saying great
I would have the enterprise I would have
an agent go do the same workflow.
>> Yeah.
>> And what we encourage them to really do
is think not just replicate you know Bob
does step 1 2 3 4 5 so agent is going to
do one step 1 2 3 4 5 and then Bob's
going to check it at the end. That's not
really the model you want. You want to
actually step back and say if I want to
accomplish something how can an agent do
it differently? It can do it in a
massively parallelized way. can try 50
different things and get to that and and
how do you help it get to that right
outcome and rethink how a computer would
solve a problem versus a human solving a
problem. And so one of the things is us
just helping customers understand how to
think about that and really kind of have
that blank slate because that's where
you really get value is not just
replicating what you're doing today but
but thinking from a green field approach
about how you go solve a problem
completely differently and I'm sure
that's how many of your startups are
thinking about this too which is how do
you help customers green field solve a
problem not replicate the thing that
happens today.
>> So that that is number one
>> people running fleets of agents swarms
whatever you want to call them. Yeah,
>> very common these days
>> and and and you just want to think about
it, you know, and and so enterprises are
not as as again this is one where you
learn from the startups and you try to
how do you apply that to an enterprise
world where they're, you know, an
insurance company is not necessarily as
forwardleaning, but they would love to
figure out how they can have a better um
you know, approval workflow or something
like that. Um so that's number one, but
then the second one is this this how do
you turn those into fully autonomous
workflows and how do you actually trust
the agents? And so we're spending a lot
of time thinking about how do we build
services to help enterprises feel like
their systems are secure and that they
can trust an agent to make a decision
that they can have the right guard rails
that it can have the right permissions
on their data that it's not going to
delete production systems that it's not
going to make tragic mistakes. And right
now I think that nervousness is probably
holding people back maybe appropriately
by the way is holding enterprises back
from just saying okay go nuts. It's like
you don't actually want an agent to just
go crazy and accidentally delete a
production database. That's going to be
pretty bad.
>> Um and so you that's how we're we're
kind of actively working through this
with customers on how do we both help
them architect and frankly invent new
technologies and capabilities that are
going to help them solve that problem.
And so that that is one of the areas
where I think we'll continue to innovate
and um and and um and we'll get there. I
think we have some really good ideas um
and and some good technologies brewing
that I think can really help. So are
enterprises learning how to do eval
systems and so on and so forth to keep
the agents they need help honestly like
you like both like evals how do you have
a constant loop of testing? How do you
how do you think about um you know goal
seeking in a reasonable way? How do you
have your data labeled in such a way
that it actually even makes sense that
the eval can actually kind of um
approximate what you're going to be
doing in production? How do you measure
in production and and back test it so
you're not seeing drift? All of those
things are problems that that um
enterprises don't know how to solve
today. I shouldn't know if anyone really
is great at solving these today. Um it's
why you've seen so many FTE teams kind
of spin up and and AWS is um and our
partners are really leaning into the the
FDE motion to go and help and this is
the single biggest area where customers
need help and and when we think about
how you you you and
my view is we want to train our
customers to be able to go and do this
themselves, right? This is not the
traditional notion where I want to have
a people-driven business that goes on
forever where you just keep paying
consultants over and over and over
again. our our view on how FD should
work and and and is um we want to go
into a customer who's ready to accept
the you know to really kind of accept
owning this when we're done and in 45
days do work where we can teach them how
to make an eval teach them how to get
their data in a labeled way do work
alongside with them and then at the end
of 40 to 5 days you leave and that
customer is is good and ready to go and
trained up and that's what our customers
tell us they want they don't want to be
beholden to a external workforce for the
next five Yes.
>> And um but they need help today.
>> Yeah. You made a massive investment in
>> FTEES.
>> Um so taking that even one step further,
right? Some of your industry peers have
said, look, you can't have all of your
data
going into a big frontier model. What
enterprises should really do is to take
an open source model and then post train
on your own data and workflows and
phrases and whatnot.
>> Where do you stand on that? Are you
seeing customers actually trying to do
that or do you guys
>> how do you how do you think about that?
>> It's it's a great the first point I I
wholeheartedly agree on that first point
like the customers and like enterprise
data is their most valuable asset.
>> And so from the very beginning it's why
we built Bedrock like we did. Um we have
a guarantee that your data never leaves
your VPC. And so your if you're running
inside of Bedrock um your data doesn't
go back to the model provider. They
never see your prompts. um that stays
inside of your own trusted environment.
Um and so that that is why um
enterprises kind of run they they prefer
to run on top of bedrock and it's why
you see that business growing massively
like hundreds and hundreds I mean it's
every um every month we see that just
business just every week we see that
business exploding and and it's why um
you see open AI workloads migrating to
bedrock. It's why you see Anthropic
really growing really rapidly. And so
whether you're using open models or um
uh or or um closed frontier models. Um I
think bedrock is a great solution that
our our customers told us by the way
like you know we if you remember 3 years
ago I got a lot of heat.
>> Speaking of bad names, that's a good
name though.
>> Yeah, Bedrock is a good name. That's
good. But we we got a lot of heat
actually for being slow to the AI world
because we actually built the
foundations of this where we said look
we're not just going to rush out of
service. We really want to think about
how do we make sure that we protect our
customers data and build a service that
we think is going to be durable for the
use cases that we knew about. And if you
remember we got a lot of heat and we
said look we're going to go build the
right thing and now as people move from
proof of concepts to production vast
majority of them are landing in AWS on
bedrock for for much one of the reasons
is because of this. It's also because of
the the set of services that we have. We
also offer open models. We offer
proprietary models. Um we offer um a
whole set of capabilities around those
agent core. We build these building
blocks so it's easier to build agents
with any of the models that you want.
>> Um whether they're in bedrock or out of
bedrock for that matter. You can use
Gemini or other things for it. But um
but I think that's a it's a it's a
differentiating piece for us and it's a
super important thing to think about
because
>> having that data go back into the the
model provider I think is a is a
dangerous thing. You talk about open
weights models though. I do think that
there's a and it's an area that I'm
excited about. um uh we're we're really
ramping up our support of open weights
models and and trying to build a good um
environment and and frankly this is
where today I think and I think it's
true a lot of customers believe that
they have meaningful proprietary data
that if they could mix in you know do
some post- training do some fine-tuning
um um to an open weights model that they
could distill down they could actually
get a better performing model at a lower
price. Um there's a bunch of pieces in
here that have to work out well. They
actually have a good eval to actually
prove that that's true. Most people are
doing that in SageMaker today. I think
there's more that we can do to make that
easier. But actually like if you go look
at where are people doing that, they
actually do it in SageMaker on AWS today
and they actually host the inference via
SageMaker.
>> SageMaker is getting a new lease of life
as a
>> uh I mean it is it's it was always kind
of a model building platform, right? And
now you know there's if if you think
about what enterprises are doing in this
world that's what they're doing is
they're basically effectively building
their own custom models. And so that is
SageMaker is is a great place of doing
that. Um and I think there's some things
that we need to keep building on to make
that easier and easier to do
>> um and to test across different open
weights models and things like that. But
that's a um it's a it's an evolving
space. I think it's a super interesting
one and it's one we want to make sure
that we have all the right things for um
for customers to be able to do if they
if they have the the right data and
expertise to actually go down that path
>> and with all the debate around AI
extension risk and this that and the
other and the security um uh
vulnerabilities and so on and so forth
and the hugging face attack. [snorts]
How are enterprise what do what are CEOs
asking you about all these things? Yeah,
that there's a bunch and and they look
they they mostly want to say like and it
goes back to this like when I launch
agents, how can I trust that they're
going to do what I want them to do? And
so we're in increasingly
>> we have been for a while like we're
basically we're heavily investing in
building capabilities that allow people
to deploy agents safely into their
environment and think about those
controls. And some of those are how do
you make sure the agents have the right
permissions? How do they have the right
sandboxing? How do you make sure that
you have the right set of guardrails?
How do you how do you really
intentionally think about what you want
the agents to do and not do? Is there a
human in the loop or not? And so we we
spend a lot of time with our customers
thinking about how do you think about
safe agent deployment and get better
over time and um and what other
capabilities do we need to go build to
help people deploy agents safely into
their environment. Um so there there's a
lot there. Um the other a the other
angle on that which um a lot of people
are worried about which is just um are
some of these really powerful models
going to be um attack services and and
and kind of mythosphere um and so I I
kind of have a view on there they're yes
that is a real risk I think to to
customer environments but it's also um a
real opportunity and so we we recently
launched a service called continuum that
uses these powerful models to help
customers go secure their environment
and So, we'll look across our
environment, uh, look for
vulnerabilities with them. We'll use
some of these powerful models and and,
um, um, and help customers find
vulnerabilities they haven't found
before. And most importantly, by the
way, prioritize which ones cuz we know
context about their environment, how
it's set up, where their permissions
are, where they may have compensating
controls that that make it harder or
easier to do. Um, and so Continuum is
incredibly popular with customers.
Actually, we're um um um really bullish
about what's possible from AI to help
with AI powered security cuz look at at
some point customers are going to need
security at machine speed, not at at
human speed, not at like an alarm
someone goes in look at it.
>> And so that you know we're running fast
to go help build that for customers to
help them protect their environments and
and I'm very excited about the the
continuum team is building on that front
too. So within AWS itself
>> Mhm.
>> like how what's the state of adop usage
of
agents in the broad and
>> well continuum is basically us trying to
expose what we do internally and so we
we use uh AI extensively for our own
security. We use AI extensively for our
own software development. Uh we use uh
agents actually one of the things that's
really cool is we use agents across our
entire business. And so we we rolled out
um Amazon Quick to every single Amazon
employee. And now I see HR teams
building agents to to help drive what
what used to take teams of people weeks
to do that a single person can now do in
a couple of hours to think about kind of
team planning and and and resource
management. Um I have finance teams that
are building um agents to to go think
about how do they go pull tax rules from
everywhere and ensure that we have
compliance on a bunch of different
pieces. And um super cool to see that
things that used to be blocked by
software developers
>> actually the the the line of business
folks are able to go and and unblock
themselves and and innovate more
quickly. Um and so Quick has been an
enormous blow and and that has has grown
like wildfire. see um customers like
small startups using it all the way to
the the largest enterprises in the world
rolling it out to their entire customer
base to get the benefit of kind of being
able to access all of your enterprise
data and easily apply agents and and
capabilities to to help you accelerate
your jobs. And so I said we use it
across uh everything from software
development to security to um to to
driving HR policies. I mean you guys are
notorious for measuring every everything
about your operation. Where have you
seen the biggest gains? Yeah, it's I
mean obviously you know the answer
software development like that's the
real answer
>> the derivatives of that
>> but yeah I mean the software I mean the
speed of software development has been
uh and and and really product
development uh as a whole not just
coding
>> actual
>> absolutely the the case at which we're
deploying new products is is um is
massively different than it has been in
the past. I think you can see this where
you know AWS has always been known for
rolling out features really quickly and
uh and it's you know we've we've seen a
turbo boost on that in the last year or
so as as we've get we call them frontier
teams as they think about agentic
development as opposed to kind of
traditional development and it's you
know it's not code completion it really
is agent first the agents write all of
the code you're just managing a team of
agents and and driving that um and it's
it's been fun to see the the the pace at
which um innovations for customers has
has been massive and um and it has to be
cuz that's the that's the our customers
out there have a a almost insatable
appetite for new capabilities and and
that's what we got to do.
>> Yeah. So organizationally are you like
do you have any insights on how
organizations should change and how
[sighs]
>> I don't uh I'll say that
>> agents manage people manage agents
[laughter]
>> uh there's like there's going to be
there's going to be lots of people for a
long period of time. I do think
organizations will change. I don't know
the magic answer yet. Um but but we're
actively thinking
>> inside you're just trying various
experiments or what?
>> We're trying experiments. We're thinking
about pods. Um as you think about you
know here's one example is in a product
organization you used to have a team
that would own a particular kind of
capability for a long time and you might
have 10 people working on that thing.
Well today you can innovate so rapidly
that one doesn't have to be 10 people.
It can be three to four people
>> and they build something so fast, you
actually want to move them to different
projects and and problems. And so
thinking about how do you both operate
and and maintain the things that you
built while being agile and flexible to
move around on an organization that's as
big as AWS is as active things that
we're experimenting with and playing
with. But it's um it's fun and it's
enabling for our employees. They
actually love it because they can build
faster and do more. But um but there's
real work there.
>> Yeah, it's a fascinating time and uh so
thank you very much for your time. We
could be talking about this for hours
together, but uh thanks for all your
insights.
>> Yeah, thank you for having me and uh and
thank you. We we we love having uh all
your uh your companies as customers and
uh we love learning from them and uh I
appreciate having me here.
>> Yeah, we'll keep sending them your way.
>> Excellent. Thank you.
>> Thanks.